# **Kevin John**

# Senior Software Engineer

kevinjohnoo318@gmail.com 📞 06543 77 55 68 👂 Niederweiler

# **PROFILE**

Have +6 years of extensive experience working in Javascript/Typescript frameworks such as Express, React, Vue and Angular

Have 3 years of extensive development experience in Blockchain, EVM based smart contract development using Solidity and Vyper,

and Web3 integration

An interest and passion for working on Blockchain-based systems, ranging from DeFi, to NFTs, to decentralized exchanges

Experience as a core member of a software development team with significant contributions

Software design experience with architectures that have scaled from the simple to the complex

Be excited to work in an environment that involves continual adaptation and change, be open to picking up new technologies and

frameworks

#### LANGUAGES

english

# **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor's of Computer Science**

Heidelberg University

04/2008 - 05/2012 Heidelberg, germany

#### SKILLS

# **Programming Language**

javascript typescript python php

#### Frameworks and Libraries

¡Query ExpressJs Angular React Vue.js Laravel Django

#### **Database System**

MongoDB MySQL PostgreSQL pinecone

# Cloud provider

**AWS** 

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Front-End Dev 09/2015 - 05/2018 KOKOEN GMBH Saarbrücken,,

Work directly with founders and collaborate on feature discovery, ideation and

Meeting with the development team to discuss user interface ideas and applications.

Reviewing application requirements and interface designs.

Developing and implementing highly responsive user interface components using react concepts.

Writing application interface codes using JavaScript following react.js workflows.

Troubleshooting interface software and debugging application codes.

Developing and implementing front-end architecture to support user interface concepts.

Monitoring and improving front-end performance.

Documenting application changes and developing updates.

#### **Full-Stack Web Dev**

07/2012 - 08/2015 QIMIA GMBH Köln, germany

Research, UI / UI design and implement technical specifications for the product based on client requirement.

Germany

Ensure projects are built to meet performance, security, SEO, and functional client requirement.

Assist with testing, debugging, documentation, and overall quality assurance of projects. Involved in the requirement analysis,

design, development, review, deployment as well as in the testing of the project. After service for individual client and upgrade website based on client desired feature and revamp the website on a quart basis

# Senior Full-Stack Dev

ALAND CLOUD GMBH

Investigate and specify ideas for innovative blockchain applications.

Design and develop proof of concepts for blockchain applications.

Design and develop blockchain related microservices and APIs comfortably.

Plan and execute performance tests using test-driven development.

Manage individual project priorities, deadlines, and deliverables

Work with the team to tackle complex challenges associated with blockchain and other Web3

technologies

# Full-Stack Blockchain Dev

**CUBEWARE** 

Research, develop, and test various technologies based on blockchain
Build the protocol components that integrate across different blockchain systems
Build smart contracts in Solidity for EVM blockchain
Design, scope, and estimate complex contract based on requirements given
Writing efficient, scalable, robust, and maintainable code
Enthusiastically collaborate with a small team to plan projects at the task level
Collaborate with cross functional partners on all aspects of product development
Senior Full-Stack D

11/2018 – 09/2020 Berlin, Germany

11/2020 – 08/2023 München, Germany